[Music]
my dreams
are like the tamarack trees glowing
amber with
needles of gold under a hunter's moon i
dance with the dryads and they tell me
their secrets
the mountain slopes are vigilant and so
i become
anticipating the frost and the
diminishing light
so
[Music]
do
october is a month of change and i find
myself
quite excited for the cold weather it is
an opportunity to prepare one's mind for
a period of rest i take great
inspiration from animals during this
time
many are gathering food knowing what is
to come
they will diminish as the snow comes and
patiently wait
i as well consider what it is that i
truly need in my life
be it good company more sleep a clean
space
i do my best to prepare for both the
time of hardship
and renewal but i also think about my
heart
and what feelings need to be cultivated
there
[Music]
one thing that has been on my mind
recently is wishing for a world that is
more compassionate
i've always been sensitive and
empathetic by nature
sometimes to a fault but i know that i
can be even more compassionate
because every day i'm reminded of this
by the children
i work with
my job as a teacher gives me an
opportunity to practice empathy every
day
indeed when a two-year-old has been
crying over a scraped knee for an hour
it can be quite exhausting but in those
moments i remember that that scrape knee
may very well be the worst pain they
have ever experienced in their short
lifetime
considering that the reaction seems
suddenly
appropriate
i think we can apply this same concept
to adults as well
we are each on our own journey many of
us have endured different types of
hardship
and pain but it feels different for each
of us
since the experience is unique and we
are all in need of compassionate words
and actions
no one is stronger or weaker due to
their emotional or
less emotional spirit i believe our
strength is shown through our actions
towards others
not how often we cry
[Music]
do
so
as you can see today is one of my days
off
i'm not working and therefore i'm left
to my own devices
i deeply enjoy these days by myself
even though i welcome a future where a
family and children takes up more of my
time
but right now this is where i am in my
life and i wish to take full advantage
of each delicious minute
i spend it working on my crafts cooking
painting
but most importantly daydreaming
have you recently spent a moment simply
with your own thoughts
letting your imagination take flight to
places you have never seen before it is
one of my favorite pastimes
one that children seem to innately
understand
i implore you to never stop daydreaming
in moments where the harsh realities of
the world find me feeling anger and
despair
this is healing i spend time every day
nursing a vibrant imagination and rich
spiritual life
these are two things that are so
separate and yet for me
also innately intertwined they both
involve seeing the world as full of
goodness
as it is in need of compassion a
peaceful coexistence
is possible because i've seen it in my
heart
spirit and mind even if it is not yet
tangible
in the real world as the cold sets in
and i prepare to hibernate in my free
time
i know that i will spend much of it
dreaming and i hope
you will too
[Music]
do
you